<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Conditions to be obserued by the Brittish vndertakers of the escheated lands in Vlster consisting in three principall points, viz. 1. What the Brittish vndertakers shall haue of his Maiesties gift. 2. What the said vndertakers shall for their parts performe. 3. In what manner the same performance shall be.</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1610</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A14202</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 24516</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S121225</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99856410</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99856410</idno>
            <idno type="VID">21959</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A14202)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 21959)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1119:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Conditions to be obserued by the Brittish vndertakers of the escheated lands in Vlster consisting in three principall points, viz. 1. What the Brittish vndertakers shall haue of his Maiesties gift. 2. What the said vndertakers shall for their parts performe. 3. In what manner the same performance shall be.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 11, [3] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, printer to the Kings most excellent Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno Dom. 1610.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>The words "1. What the Brittish .. shall be." are enclosed in horizontal brackets on title page.</note>
                  <note>Royal arms on title page verso.</note>
                  <note>The last leaf is blank.</note>
                  <note>A different text from STC 24515, though with some parallels.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ulster (Ireland) --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England --  Foreign relations --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:21959:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:21959:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:21959:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:21959:2"/>
            <p>CONDITIONS TO BE OBSERVED by the <hi>Brittiſh</hi> Vndertakers of the Eſcheated Lands in VLSTER, Conſiſting in three principall points, <hi>Viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <list>
               <item>1. What the Brittiſh Vndertakers ſhall haue of his Maieſties gift.</item>
               <item>2. What the ſaid Vndertakers ſhall for their parts performe.</item>
               <item>3. In what manner the ſame perfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mance ſhall be.</item>
            </list>
            <p>¶ <hi>Jmprinted at London by</hi> Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Barker, Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Maieſtie. ANNO DOM. 1610.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="illustration">
            <pb facs="tcp:21959:3"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:21959:3"/>
            <head>CONDITIONS TO <hi>BE OBSER<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ED BY the</hi> Brittiſh <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ndertakers</hi> of the Eſcheated Lands in VLSTER, &amp;c.</head>
            <div n="1" type="part">
               <head>I. What the <hi>Brittiſh</hi> Vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dertakers ſhall haue.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Irſt,<note place="margin">The Praecincts.</note> the Landes to be vndertaken by them, are diuided into ſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dry <hi>Praecincts,</hi> of diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent quantities.</p>
               <p>Euery <hi>Praecinct</hi> is ſubdiuided into <hi>Proportions</hi> of three ſorts,<note place="margin">The Proportions</note> 
                  <hi>Great, Middle,</hi> and <hi>Small.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The great <hi>Proportion</hi> containeth 2000. Engliſh Acres at the leaſt.</p>
               <p>The middle <hi>Proportion</hi> co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>taineth 1500. Acres at the leaſt.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="2" facs="tcp:21959:4"/>The ſmall <hi>Proportion</hi> containeth 1000. Acres at the leaſt.</p>
               <p>Vnto euery of which <hi>Proportions</hi> ſuch bogge and wood ſhall be allowed, as lieth within the ſame, for which no Rent ſhalbe reſerued.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">The diſtribution of the Praecincts.</note>The <hi>Praecincts</hi> are by name diſtin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſhed, part for the <hi>Engliſh,</hi> and part for the <hi>Scottiſh,</hi> as appeareth by the Table of <hi>Diſtribution</hi> of the <hi>Praecincts.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Euery <hi>Praecinct</hi> ſhalbe aſsigned to one principall Vndertaker, and his conſort, as will appeare by the Table of Aſsignati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the <hi>Praecincts.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The chiefe Vndertakers ſhalbe allowed two middle <hi>Proportions,</hi> if they deſire the ſame; otherwiſe no one Vndertaker is to be allowed aboue one great <hi>Proportion.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Their eſtates.</note>They ſhall haue an eſtate in <hi>Fee Simple</hi> to them and their heires.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Power to create Tenures.</note>They ſhall haue power to create Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nours, to hold <hi>Courts Baron</hi> twice euery yeere, and not oftner, and power to create <hi>Tenures in Socage</hi> to hold of themſelues.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">Libertie of ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation.</note>They, their heires and aſsignes, for the
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:21959:4"/>
ſpace of 7. yeeres next enſuing, ſhall haue libertie to export out of <hi>Ireland</hi> all com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities growing or arriſing vpon their owne Lands vndertaken, without paying Cuſtome or Impoſition.</p>
               <p>They, their heires and Aſsignes,<note place="margin">Libertie of im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation.</note> for the ſpace of 5. yeeres next enſuing, ſhall haue freedome to import into <hi>Ireland</hi> out of <hi>Great Britaine,</hi> victuall, and vtenſiles for their Houſholds, materials and tooles for their buildings and Husbandry, and cattell to ſtocke and manure the Lands vnder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taken, without paying any Cuſtome or Impoſition; which ſhall not extend to any commodities tranſported by way of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandiſe.</p>
               <p>They ſhall haue allowance of Timber for their buildings to be erected vpon their <hi>Proportions,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Allowance of Timber.</note> the ſame to be taken in any of the <hi>Praecincts,</hi> by the Aſsignment of the Commiſsioners, without paying anything for the ſame for the ſpace of two yeeres; And after that time expired, euery Vnder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taker to hold to his owne vſe the Timber and Woods remayning vpon his owne <hi>Proportion.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="4" facs="tcp:21959:5"/>
                  <note place="margin">Aduowſons.</note>The principall Vndertaker ſhall haue one Aduowſon within his <hi>Praecinct,</hi> to him and his heires.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="part">
               <head>2. What the ſaid Vnder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers ſhall for their parts performe.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">1. Their Rent.</note>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hey ſhall yeerely yeeld vnto his Maieſtie for euery <hi>Proportion</hi> of 1000. Acres, fiue pound ſixe ſhillings eight pence Engliſh, and ſo rateably for the great <hi>Proportions;</hi> The firſt halfe yeeres payment to begin at Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaelmas 1614.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">2. Their Tenure.</note>Euery of the ſaid Vndertakers ſhal hold the Lands ſo vndertaken in <hi>Free and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Socage,</hi> as of the Caſtle of <hi>Dublin,</hi> and by no greater Seruice.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">3. Their Building.</note>Euery of the ſaid Vndertakers of a great <hi>Proportion,</hi> ſhall within 3. yeeres to be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compted from Eaſter next, build there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon a ſtone houſe, with a ſtrong court or bawne about it; And euery Vndertaker
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:21959:5"/>
of a middle <hi>Proportion,</hi> ſhall within the ſame time build a ſtone or bricke houſe thereupon, with a ſtrong court or bawne about it; And euery Vndertaker of a ſmall <hi>Proportion,</hi> ſhal within the ſame time make thereupon a ſtrong Court or bawne at leaſt.</p>
               <p>Euery Vndertaker ſhall within three yeeres, to be accompted from Eaſter next,<note place="margin">4. Their Families.</note> plant or place vpon a ſmall <hi>Proportion,</hi> the number of 24. able men of the age of 18. yeeres or vpwards, being Engliſh, or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land Scottiſh; And ſo rateably vpon the other <hi>Proportions;</hi> Which numbers ſhall be reduced into 10. families at leaſt, to be ſetled vpon euery ſmall <hi>Proportion,</hi> and rateably vpon the other <hi>Proportions</hi> in this maner; Viz. The principall Vndertaker and his family to bee ſetled vpon a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meſne of 300. Acres; Two Fee-fermours vpon 120. Acres a piece; Three Leaſehol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders for three liues or 21. yeeres vpon 100. Acres apiece; And vpon the reſidue being 160. Acres, foure families or more of Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bandmen, Artificers or Cottagers; their
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:21959:6"/>
                  <hi>Portions</hi> of Land to bee aſsigned by the principall Vndertaker at his diſcretion.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">5 The Building of the vnder-Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants.</note>Euery of the ſaid Vndertakers ſhall draw their Tenants to build houſes for themſelues and their families, not ſcatte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, but together, neere the principall houſe or bawne, aſwell for their mutuall defence and ſtrength, as for the making of Villages and Towneſhips.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">6 Armes.</note>The ſaid Vndertakers, their heires and aſsignes, ſhall haue ready in their houſes at all times, a conuenient ſtore of Armes, wherewith they may furniſh a competent number of men for their defence, which may be viewed and muſtered euery halfe yeere, according to the maner of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">7. Oath of Supre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>macie.</note>Euery of the ſaid Vndertakers, before he be receiued to be an Vndertaker, ſhall take the Oath of Supremacie, either in the Chancerie of <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Scotland,</hi> or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Commiſsioners to bee appointed for the eſtabliſhing of the <hi>Plantation;</hi> And ſhall alſo conforme themſelues in Religion according to his Maieſties Lawes; And
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:21959:6"/>
euery of their Vndertenants being chiefe of a family, ſhall take the like Oath before the ſaid Commiſsioners, or the Iuſtices of Aſsize comming into the Countie, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaid Tenants ſhall be placed at the next Aſsizes, after they ſhall ſit downe and inhabite in the ſaid ſeuerall Counties. And they and their families, ſhall be alſo con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formable in Religion as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>Euery of the ſaid Vndertakers for the ſpace of fiue yeeres,<note place="margin">8. Reſidence.</note> to be accompted from Michaelmas next, ſhall be reſident him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe in perſon vpon his <hi>Portion,</hi> or place ſome ſuch other perſon thereupon, as ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>be allowed by the State of <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> And ſhall take the Oath of Suprema<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cie; and likewiſe be himſelfe with his fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily conformable in Religion as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, who ſhall be reſident during the ſaid fiue yeeres, vnleſſe by reaſon of ſickneſſe or other important cauſe, he be licenſed by the Lord Deputie and Councell of <hi>Ireland</hi> to abſent himſelfe for a time.</p>
               <p>The ſaid Vndertakers,<note place="margin">9. Reſtraint of Alie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation to the Iriſh.</note> their heires and aſsignes, ſhall not Alien or demiſe their
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:21959:7"/>
                  <hi>Portions</hi> or any part thereof to the meere <hi>Iriſh,</hi> or to ſuch perſons as will not take the ſaid Oath of Supremacie; And to that end a <hi>prouiſo</hi> ſhall be inſerted in their Letters Patents, that the parcell of land ſo aliened ſhalbe forfeited.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">10. Reſtraint of Alie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation within fiue yeeres.</note>The ſaid Vndertakers ſhall not Alien their <hi>Portions</hi> during fiue yeeres, to be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compted from Michaelmas next; but vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to their Vndertenants, in the forme before expreſſed in the fourth Article.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">11. Vncertein Rents.</note>The ſaid Vndertakers ſhall not reſerue any vncertaine Rent, but the ſame ſhall be expreſly ſet downe without reference to the cuſtome of the Countrey.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="part">
               <head>3. In what maner the ſaid performance ſhall be.</head>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">1. To repaire into Ireland before Midſo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mer next.</note>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He ſaid Vndertakers ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in perſon, or by ſuch Agents as ſhall be allowed by the Councels of Eſtate of <hi>England</hi> or <hi>Scotland</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectiuely, ſhall before Midſommer day
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:21959:7"/>
next, repaire into the Realme of <hi>Ireland,</hi> and offer themſelues to the Lord Deputie and Commiſsioners for the Plantation; who ſhal take order with the ſaid Vnder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers for the diſtribution of the <hi>Proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons</hi> within euery Precinct, either by A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greement or Lot; So as euery Vndertaker ſhall know his <hi>Portion,</hi> if the ſame be not diſtributed here in <hi>England</hi> before.</p>
               <p>The ſaid Vndertakers by themſelues or their ſaid Agents,<note place="margin">2. To ſit downe be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fore Michaelmas next.</note> ſhall take poſſeſsion of their ſeuerall <hi>Portions,</hi> and ſit downe vpon the ſame before Michaelmas next.</p>
               <p>The ſaid Vndertakers ſhall bring ouer into <hi>Ireland,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">3. Time of placing their Tenants.</note> and plant and place vpon their ſeuerall <hi>Proportions,</hi> the ſeuerall numbers of men and families aforeſaid, <hi>Viz.</hi> One third part before the feaſt of All Saints next, an other thirde part before the firſt day of May then next enſuing, and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther third part before the feaſt of All Saints in the yeere of our Lord God one Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſixe hundreth and eleuen.</p>
               <p>The ſaid Vndertakers ſhall take out<note place="margin">4. Time of taking out their Patents.</note> their Letters Patents either in <hi>England</hi> or
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:21959:8"/>
in <hi>Ireland,</hi> at their election, before Mid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſommer day next.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">5. By what degrees they ſhall erect their habitations and buildings.</note>The ſayd Vndertakers ſhall before the feaſt of <hi>All Saints</hi> next make their ſeuerall Courts or Bawnes vpon their <hi>Proportions,</hi> and erect habitations for one third part of the men and families which they are to plant thereupon; And before the firſt day of May then next enſuing, they ſhall erect habitations for one other third part, and prouide and bring in place all the materi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als for building of their Stone houſes; And before the feaſt of <hi>All Saints</hi> 1611. follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, they ſhall erect habitations for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidue of their men and families, and in the meane time proceed in the building of their Stone-houſes, ſo as they may be fully finiſhed within three yeeres as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>
                  <note place="margin">6. Their Bonds or Recogniſances for performance of the Articles of Plantation.</note>Euery Vndertaker before the enſealing of their Letters Patents, ſhall enter into bond or recognizance with good ſureties to his Maieſties vſe, in the Office of his Maieſties chiefe Remembrancer in Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land or Ireland, or in his Maieſties Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer or Chancery in Scotland, to performe
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:21959:8"/>
the aforeſaid Articles according to the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uerall diſtinctions of <hi>Building, Planting, Reſidence, Alienation</hi> within fiue yeeres, and <hi>making of certain eſtates</hi> to their Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants, viz. The Vndertaker of the greateſt <hi>Proportion</hi> to become bound in foure hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds; of the middle, in three hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds; of the leaſt, in two hundred pounds: which bands or recognizances ſhall be deliuered vp after fiue yeeres vpon Certificate of the L. Deputie and Counſel, that the true meaning of the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditions thereof hath bene performed.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
